1.
Mathematics is the language of nature.
2.
Everything around us can be represented and understood through numbers.
3.
As you graph the numbers of any system, patterns emerge.
4.
Therefore, there are patterns everywhere in nature.
5.
Staying, collateral, rhombus, trapezoid.
I'm asking you to do what I'm asking everyone in that room.
All my genius is to look beyond the numbers.
Look around through them.
The answer to the questions we don't even know how to ask.
And if it doesn't yet, it's just...
Because without it, we're not going anywhere.
We're staying on the ground, we're not flying into space, we're not circling the Earth, and we're certainly not touching it.
But in my mind...
In my mind, I'm always there.
Are you?
If you can keep your head when all about you are losing theirs and blaming it on you.
If you can trust yourself when all men doubt you, and make allowance for their doubting too.
If you can wait and not be tired by waiting.
Or being lied about, don't deal in lies.
Or being hated, don't give way to hating.
And yet, don't look too good, nor talk too wise.
I've been trying to solve the equation without changing the underlying assumption about time.
If you can dream, and not make dreams your master.
If you can think, and not make thoughts your aim.
If you can meet with triumph and disaster, and treat those two imposters just the same.
If you can bear to hear the truth you've spoken, twisted by nays to make trap for fools.
Or watch the things you gave your life to, broken, and stoop and build them up with worn out tools.
If you can make one heap of all your winnings, and risk it on one turn, and pitch and toss.
And lose, and start again at your beginnings, and never breathe a word about your loss.
If you can force your heart and nerve and sinew to serve your turn long after they are gone.
And so hold on when there is nothing in you, except the will that says to them, hold on.
Then let's succeed.
If you can talk with crowds, and keep your virtue.
Or walk with kings, nor lose the common touch.
If neither foes, nor loving friends can hurt you.
If all men count with you, but none too much.
If you can fill the unforgiving minute, with sixty seconds worth of distance run.
Yours is the earth, and everything that's in it.
And which is more, you'll be a man my son.
Did you just solve Rima?
You think you can find me the Fermi frame from this data?
In the Graham Schmidt?
What's the organization algorithm you said?
I prefer it over you, Corwin Corwin.
The probability of happiness.
You're close.
Some integer of zero, but no.
You were right.
Cause she's theorem will work.
Before I had a thirty three point three percent chance of choosing right.
But after he opens one of the doors, and then he offers me the choice, it's now sixty six point seven percent.
Simple, elegant equation, explain everything.
As you will find in the multiverbal calculus notes, I've known a number of solutions for any given problem.
Math is always the pinball.
Invent yourself, and then reinvent yourself.
Don't swim in the same slough.
And stay out of the clutches of mediocrity.
Invent yourself, and then reinvent yourself.
Change your tone and shape so often that they can never categorize you.
Reinvigorate yourself, and accept what is.
Put only on the terms that you have invented and reinvented.
Be self-taught.
And reinvent your life, because you must.
It is your life, and its history and the present, belong only to you.